Guide to the Willie and Truman Teeter Collection 1956-2004
Pacific University Archives
Willie and Truman Teeter Collection
1956-2004
MS.99
Pacific University, Archives http://www.pacificu.edu/library/services/archives/ 2043 College Way Forest Grove, OR, 97116 503-352-1405 archives@pacificu.edu
1.5 cubic feet 1 box, 1 oversize folder and 1 object
Willie and Truman Teeter were a married pair of staff and faculty members at Pacific University, where they worked for many years. This collection consists of photographs, awards, yearbooks, publications and memorabilia that they collected through their connections to Pacific.
Teeter, Truman E., 1918-2001; Teeter, Willie (Wilberta Winniford)
Biographical Note
Willie and Truman Teeter were a married pair of staff and faculty members at Pacific University, where they worked for many years. Willie, also known as "Mrs. T," was a well-known and well-loved staff member at the Pacific University School of Optometry from the 1960s through the 1990s, when she retired. Truman was a professor of chemistry.
This collection consists of photographs, awards, yearbooks, publications and memorabilia that Wille and Truman Teeter collected. Most of the material is related to their connections to Pacific University, such as awards that Willie Teeter won for her service as a staff member. Several issues of "The Optimist," the yearbook of Forest Grove High School from their daughter's time there, are also present.
Note: Cookbooks that belonged to Willie Teeter are cataloged separately, under MS.100. Yearbooks and runs of Pacific University publications donated by the Teeters were added to existing runs of the same publications in the Archives. Additional books from the Teeter Family were donated to the Pacific University Library for its general circulating collection.
Donated by the Teeter Family to Pacific University, October 2012.
Some student records in this collection may need to be restricted due to privacy concerns.
Pacific University; Universities and colleges--Oregon
Photographs
Faculty Member, College or University
- Awards
  - Willie Teeter honorary certificate of appreciation bestowed by President Duvall at Commencement, 1990
  - Willie Teeter honorary Doctor of Optometry degree from Pacific University, 1990
  - Willie Teeter plaque, "An award of thanks and love from the student body of Pacific University College of Optometry.", 1985
  - Willie Teeter "Tabbie" award for service to Pacific University, 2002
  - Willie Teeter trophy: "Prism Staff Appreciation Award" from the School of Optometry., 1996
    Trophy shelved alongside the collection.
  - Willie Teeter University Service Award, 1989
- Photographs
  - Pacific University Optometry School student life snapshots, 1960-1990
  - Pacific University School of Optometry oversized class portrait posters, 1971-1993
    Includes classes of 1971, 1973-1993. Housed in oversized drawer 7.
  - Willie Teeter receiving her honorary Doctor of Optometry degree, 1990
- Memorabilia and Other Documents
  - Christmas cards to Willie Teeter, signed by students from the School of Optometry, 1975?-1989
  - "Memento to the Graduate": scrolls created by the Pacific University Guild for Pacific students, 1966
  - Newspaper clippings related to the Teeters, 1970-2000
  - Pacific University College of Optometry alumni luncheon program, 1996
  - Truman Teeter class grade books and student advisee reports (restricted), 1964-1976
    Due to student privacy concerns, this material is restricted. Please contact archives for information regarding access.
  - Truman Teeter hood from his academic regalia, 1960s?
  - Truman Teeter transparency slides used in classes, 1970s?
  - United Church of Christ Women's Fellowship program, 1996-1997
  - Yearbooks, "The Optimist," Forest Grove High School. Includes handwritten notes addressed to the Teeters' daughter, Ann., 1970-1973